Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine and welcome everyone.
我是Katherine，欢迎大家。
Today we've got an elementary level lesson for you.
今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程。
It's all about sending things through the mail.
内容是关于通过邮寄寄送物品。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe gifts, maybe letters.
可能是礼物，也可能是信件。
We're going to the post office so why don't we jump right into this dialogue.
我们要去邮局，所以不如直接进入这段对话吧。
Let's listen to it for the first time and we'll be right back.
我们先听一遍，然后马上回来。
Hi I would like to send this package to China and these postcards as well.
你好，我想把这个包裹寄到中国，还有这些明信片。
Very well.
好的。
You will need some stamps for the postcards and I need to weigh that package too.
明信片需要贴邮票，我还得称一下那个包裹。
Great.
太好了。
How much is this going to cost?
这要花多少钱？
Well it depends.
嗯，这要看情况。
Do you want to send it via priority, express or standard mail?
您想用优先、快递还是标准邮寄？
What's the difference?
有什么区别？
Well standard mail can take up to 15 working days.
标准邮寄最多需要15个工作日。
Priority is a bit faster and will arrive in about 5 to 8 working days.
优先邮寄快一些，大约5到8个工作日到达。
Express is the fastest but it's also the most expensive.
快递是最快的，但也是最贵的。
It only takes three days and you can track your package online.
只需三天，你就可以在线追踪包裹。
I see.
我明白了。
Well there's no rush.
嗯，不急。
Please send it via priority mail.
请用优先邮件寄送。
Please be extra careful.
请格外小心。
The contents of the package are fragile.
包裹里的物品是易碎的。
All right so pretty simple dialogue.
好的，这个对话很简单。
We want to send a package through the mail.
我们想通过邮寄寄一个包裹。
So why don't we take a look at some of those mail related terms in Language Takeaway.
那么，我们来看看“语言要点”中一些与邮件相关的术语吧。
Alright so the first item we're going to talk about in today's Language Takeaway is something
好的，今天“语言要点”中我们要讨论的第一个项目是
you can send.
你可以寄送的东西。
It's called a postcard.
它叫明信片。
A postcard.
明信片。
Okay so very popular among people who are traveling and they want to send a postcard
好的，这在旅行的人中非常流行，他们想寄一张明信片
back home.
回家。
That's right.
没错。
So a postcard is something that you usually buy at a tourist destination like Walt Disney
所以明信片是你通常在旅游景点买的，比如沃尔特·迪士尼
World for example.
世界。
And it has a picture on the front and some words on the back.
它正面有图片，背面有文字。
So you can write a letter on the back of this picture.
所以你可以在图片背面写信。
So it's very simple.
所以这很简单。
It's not really a letter.
这其实不算是信。
You don't put it in an envelope.
你不用把它放进信封里。
You just write whatever you want on the back of the postcard.
你只需在明信片背面写任何你想写的内容。
But you do have to put a stamp on it in order to send it.
但你必须贴上邮票才能寄出去。
That's right.
没错。
So stamp is our next word.
所以邮票是我们的下一个词。
A stamp comes in different price ranges.
邮票有不同的价格范围。
That means that some stamps are more expensive than other stamps.
这意味着有些邮票比其他邮票更贵。
This is like money for the mail.
这就像邮件的钱一样。
So you have to buy the stamps and in order to prove that you have paid for the letter
所以你必须买邮票，为了证明你已经为你想寄的信付了钱，
that you want to send, you must place the stamps on the letter on the envelope or on
你必须把邮票贴在信上、信封上或
the postcard, right?
明信片上，对吧？
So depending on the size and weight, it costs more.
所以根据大小和重量，费用会更高。
That's right.
没错。
And usually you lick a stamp to place it on the card so it doesn't fall off.
通常你会舔一下邮票，然后贴在卡片上，这样它就不会掉下来。
True.
确实。
That's right.
没错。
You gotta lick it.
你得舔一下它。
Alright.
好的。
So as we talked about, a package can be a letter, a postcard.
正如我们之前谈到的，包裹可以是信件或明信片。
You place stamps on it and we need to weigh the package to know how much money we have
你在上面贴邮票，我们需要称重包裹才能知道要付多少钱。
to pay.
付钱。
That's right.
没错。
So sometimes a package is very heavy if it's filled with books for example.
所以有时候包裹很重，比如里面装满了书。
Sometimes it's very light if it's filled with clothes or feathers.
有时候很轻，比如里面装满了衣服或羽毛。
And so to find out how much something weighs, we have to weigh it.
为了知道某物有多重，我们必须称它。
This is a verb.
这是一个动词。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a verb, right?
所以这是一个动词，对吧？
To weigh.
称重。
So you want to know how many kilos or how many pounds this item has.
所以你想知道这个物品有多少公斤或多少磅。
Right.
对。
So we could say, it weighs a lot or how much do you weigh?
所以我们可以说，它很重，或者你多重？
Okay.
好的。
Things like this.
诸如此类。
Very good.
很好。
Alright.
好的。
Moving on, we have the different types of mailing speeds, I guess, right?
接下来，我们有不同类型的邮寄速度，对吧？
So we saw three, via priority mail, express mail or standard mail.
所以我们看到了三种：优先邮件、快递邮件或标准邮件。
So let's go in parts.
所以我们分部分来讲。
Let's go with the first one, via priority mail.
我们先讲第一个，通过优先邮件寄送。
Priority is fast.
优先就是快。
It means priority is something that's important.
它意味着优先是重要的东西。
So I have many priorities at work.
所以我在工作中有很多优先事项。
This means they're important.
这意味着它们很重要。
Very important.
非常重要。
So this letter has a certain importance.
所以这封信有一定的重要性。
It's a little bit more important than for example, the other letters.
它比其他信件稍微重要一点。
That's right.
没错。
But express is the most important, the fastest.
但特快是最重要的，最快的。
So something that's express is fast.
所以特快的东西就是快的。
Like an expressway is the fast highway.
就像高速公路是快速公路。
Express mail.
特快邮件。
Okay.
好的。
So express mail is the fastest.
所以特快邮件是最快的。
And now the normal cheapest mail is standard mail.
而现在最便宜的普通邮件是标准邮件。
Standard.
标准。
So the word standard usually means the average or the normal mail.
所以“标准”这个词通常意味着平均或普通邮件。
And in this case, it usually takes the longest.
在这种情况下，它通常花的时间最长。
Okay.
好的。
So obviously standard mail is the cheapest.
所以显然标准邮件是最便宜的。
Express mail is the most expensive because it's the fastest.
特快邮件是最贵的，因为它最快。
That's right.
没错。
So we've got all of those speeds.
所以我们有所有这些速度选项。
Now let's listen again to today's dialogue and try and listen for the words we just talked
现在让我们再听一遍今天的对话，试着听出我们刚才讨论的词汇，
about and we'll be back in a moment to talk about some important phrases.
我们稍后会回来讨论一些重要的短语。
Hi, I would like to send this package to China and these postcards as well.
你好，我想把这个包裹寄到中国，还有这些明信片。
Very well.
好的。
You will need some stamps for the postcards and I need to weigh that package too.
明信片需要贴邮票，我还得称一下那个包裹。
Great.
太好了。
How much is this going to cost?
这要花多少钱？
Well it depends.
嗯，这要看情况。
Do you want to send it via priority, express or standard mail?
你想通过优先、特快还是标准邮件寄送？
What's the difference?
有什么区别？
Well, standard mail can take up to 15 working days.
嗯，标准邮件最多需要15个工作日。
Priority is a bit faster and will arrive in about five to eight working days.
优先邮件快一点，大约五到八个工作日到达。
Express is the fastest but it's also the most expensive.
特快是最快的，但也是最贵的。
It only takes three days and you can track your package online.
只需要三天，而且你可以在网上追踪包裹。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, there's no rush.
嗯，不着急。
Please send it via priority mail.
请通过优先邮件寄送。
Please be extra careful, the contents of the package are fragile.
请特别小心，包裹里的东西易碎。
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at three key phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了，现在让我们看看流利度构建器上的三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Alright, so the first phrase today is one that I like to use a lot.
好的，今天第一个短语是我很喜欢用的一个。
We say, it depends.
我们说，这要看情况。
How much is this going to cost?
这要花多少钱？
Well, it depends.
嗯，这要看情况。
So the phrase could be, it depends.
所以这个短语可以是“这要看情况”。
So it depends.
所以“这要看情况”。
When do you usually use this?
你通常什么时候用这个？
Okay, if you ask me a question, I can have one answer but maybe there's another possible
好的，如果你问我一个问题，我可能有一个答案，但也许还有另一个可能的
answer.
答案。
For example, what are you going to wear tomorrow, Marco?
比如，马可，你明天穿什么？
It depends if it rains or not.
这要看下不下雨。
Okay, it depends.
好的，这要看情况。
If it rains, I will wear a raincoat.
如果下雨，我就穿雨衣。
If it's sunny, I will wear a normal coat.
如果晴天，我就穿普通外套。
So it depends means there is a situation or a circumstance that might change and if it
所以“这要看情况”意味着有一种情况或环境可能会改变，如果它
does, my answer will change.
变了，我的答案也会变。
Right, so it is a conditional, it depends.
对，所以这是一个条件句，这要看情况。
For example, I can ask you, what are you going to eat tonight?
比如，我可以问你，你今晚吃什么？
It depends.
这要看情况。
If I exercise, I'm going to have a hamburger and if I don't exercise, I'll have a salad.
如果我锻炼了，我就吃汉堡；如果没锻炼，我就吃沙拉。
Nice, okay.
不错，好的。
So it depends.
所以“这要看情况”。
Now we have another phrase when they were talking about how long it's going to take
现在我们还有另一个短语，当他们讨论寄东西需要多长时间时
to mail something.
用到的。
He said standard mail can take up to 15 working days.
他说标准邮件最多需要15个工作日。
So we have this little phrase there, up to.
所以我们有这个短语，“最多”。
Up to.
最多。
So up to, when you hear this, these two words together, that's an indication, it's a sign
所以“最多”，当你听到这两个词连在一起时，这是一个提示，一个标志，
that we're talking about the maximum, the most.
表示我们在谈论最大值，最多。
Okay so tomorrow, the temperature might go up to 24 degrees Celsius.
好的，所以明天温度可能高达24摄氏度。
Okay so the temperature maximum will reach 24.
好的，所以最高温度会达到24度。
It could be maybe 22, 21.
可能是22度、21度。
But not 25.
但不会是25度。
Not 25.
不会是25度。
No, because up to means the top.
不会，因为“最多”意味着上限。
So you're usually dealing with numbers, right?
所以你通常处理的是数字，对吧？
For example, this coat can cost up to $150.
例如，这件外套最高可以卖到150美元。
Wow, so the most I will spend is $150.
哇，所以我最多花150美元。
So sometimes you have a number like this when we're talking about sending a package.
所以有时候在讨论寄包裹时，你会遇到这样的数字。
We can send packages that weigh up to 10 kilos.
我们可以寄重量不超过10公斤的包裹。
Not more than 10 kilos though.
但不能超过10公斤。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And now for our last phrase to close off the dialogue, the guy said, well you know what,
现在来看我们最后一句短语来结束对话，那个人说，嗯，你知道吗，
there's no rush.
不着急。
No rush.
There's no rush.
不着急。
Okay, well the first word we want to look at here is the word rush.
好的，我们首先要看的词是“rush”。
In this case, we're talking about sending a package and the postcard, right?
这里我们在讨论寄包裹和明信片，对吧？
So does this person want it to arrive fast?
所以这个人希望它快点到吗？
He says no.
他说不。
No, there's no rush.
不，不着急。
Let's send it standard.
我们寄普通件吧。
It's cheaper.
更便宜。
Okay, so maybe your friend is like, come on, we're going to be late.
好的，所以也许你的朋友会说，快点，我们要迟到了。
And you're like, no, there's no rush.
而你会说，不，不着急。
We have one hour before the movie starts.
电影开始前我们还有一个小时。
Calm down.
冷静点。
Okay, so you're not in a hurry.
好的，所以你不赶时间。
No, there's no rush.
不，不着急。
Slow down.
慢点。
It's okay.
没事的。
This is a good one to talk about with friends or if you're working on a project at work.
这是一个和朋友聊天或工作时讨论项目的好短语。
You say, listen, there's no rush.
你说，听着，不着急。
Take your time.
慢慢来。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So let's go back to our dialogue.
那么让我们回到对话中。
Let's listen to it for the very last time and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们最后一次听一遍，然后我们稍后再回来。
Hi, I would like to send this package to China and these postcards as well.
你好，我想把这个包裹寄到中国，还有这些明信片。
Very well.
好的。
You will need some stamps for the postcards and I need to weigh that package too.
明信片需要贴邮票，我还得称一下那个包裹。
Great.
太好了。
How much is this going to cost?
这要花多少钱？
Well, it depends.
嗯，这要看情况。
Do you want to send it via priority, express or standard mail?
你想通过优先、快递还是普通邮件寄送？
What's the difference?
有什么区别？
Well, standard mail can take up to 15 working days.
嗯，普通邮件最多需要15个工作日。
Priority is a bit faster and will arrive in about five to eight working days.
优先邮件快一点，大约五到八个工作日到达。
Express is the fastest, but it's also the most expensive.
快递是最快的，但也最贵。
It only takes three days and you can track your package online.
只需要三天，你还可以在线追踪包裹。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, there's no rush.
嗯，不着急。
Please send it via priority mail.
请用优先邮件寄送。
Please be extra careful.
请格外小心。
The contents of the package are fragile.
包裹里的东西易碎。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now, Catherine, do you usually send postcards when you are abroad, when you travel?
那么，凯瑟琳，你在国外旅行时通常寄明信片吗？
Yes, I love postcards.
是的，我喜欢明信片。
And actually, I have some friends who have an amazing postcard collection.
实际上，我有一些朋友收藏了很棒的明信片。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
But it's not normal postcards.
但不是普通的明信片。
They find the most ugly postcards and they buy them and they write silly notes and they
他们找最丑的明信片，买下来，写上傻乎乎的留言，
send them to themselves.
然后寄给自己。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
I have the tradition of always sending my parents and my grandparents a postcard when
我有一个传统，在国外时总是给父母和祖父母寄明信片。
I'm abroad.
That's so sweet.
真贴心。
They have a collection of all the places you've been.
他们收藏了你去过所有地方的照片。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
So all the time, wherever I am, the first thing that I try to do if I'm in a cool place,
所以每次，无论我在哪里，如果我在一个很酷的地方，我第一件事就是
I send them a postcard.
给他们寄明信片。
And sometimes if I'm in a country in various cities and there are some nice things in,
有时候如果我在一个国家的好几个城市，有些地方有不错的东西，
for example, two or three cities, I'll send them three postcards.
比如两三个城市，我会给他们寄三张明信片。
That's awesome.
太棒了。
So do they have a book at home with all of these postcards?
所以他们家里有一本收集所有这些明信片的册子吗？
Yeah, they do.
是的，他们有。
So I just send them a little thing, how I'm doing and how great it is and wish you could
所以我只是寄给他们一点小东西，说说我过得怎么样，那里有多棒，希望你能
be here, little notes.
在这里，一些小留言。
And then they have all the collection.
然后他们就有了所有收藏。
It's really cool because that way I've actually kept track a little bit of what year and what
真的很酷，因为这样我就能稍微记录一下我在某些地方是哪一年和
date I was in certain places.
哪一天。
Wow.
哇。
Well, it's also nice because postcards, you don't need to write a very long note.
嗯，这也很好，因为明信片不需要写很长的留言。
There's no space.
没有空间。
You just write a short note.
你只需写个简短的留言。
You say, hi, how's the weather?
你说，嗨，天气怎么样？
Miss you.
想你。
Wish you were here.
希望你在这里。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So that's all the time we have for today.
今天的时间就到这里了。
But let us know if you've had any inconveniences at the post office.
但如果你在邮局遇到过任何不便，请告诉我们。
I actually had one once.
我其实就遇到过一回。
I couldn't send batteries through the mail because they have acid apparently.
我没办法通过邮件寄送电池，因为它们显然含有酸性物质。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
It's very difficult to send.
寄送起来非常困难。
So maybe you've had a situation like this before.
所以也许你以前也遇到过类似的情况。
Let us know, EnglishPod.com.
告诉我们吧，在EnglishPod.com上。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Hey, you can, too.
嘿，你也可以。